Human Rights Watch records: Record Group 4: Africa Watch 7746709
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Human Rights Watch records: Record Group 4: Africa Watch
1977-1997
1989-1995
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Human Rights Watch (Organization). Africa Watch
7746709
HRW RG 4
76.25 linear feet 61 record cartons
Record Group documents Africa Watch's (AFW) three-pronged strategy to curb human rights abuses on the Continent through reports, missions and cooperative efforts with other NGOs. First, AFW monitored abuses and produced such comprehensive reports during war as Evil Days: Thirty Years of War and Famine in Ethiopia, and Conspicuous Destruction: War, Famine and the Reform Process in Mozambique. Second, although access remained difficult in many African countries, Africa Watch was still able to conduct missions to investigate human rights conditions in Mozambique, Angola, Zimbabwe and South Africa. AFW circumvented this predicament by exchanging information gathered by local in country monitors with other NGOs. Third, besides engaging in collaborative monitoring activities, Africa Watch engaged in many joint documentation projects and lobbying efforts geared toward ending political and ethnic violence in Africa. Finally, other documentary materials include correspondence and e-mail communications, professional, personal and monitoring activity, field notes, testimonies, interviews, advocacy, policy planning material, and briefing papers.
Arrangement
This Record Group is arranged into 6 series.
Restrictions on Access
The records of Human Rights Watch are restricted unless they have been vetted and cleared for use by HRW. Specific restriction status is noted in the finding aid for each folder (open, vetted; restricted until ___; unvetted). If you wish to request boxes from this collection that have not been vetted, please send an email to rbml@columbia.edu detailing the collection, series, box, and folder numbers in which you are interested, as well as a brief description of your research needs. Once Human Rights Watch has reviewed the request, the researcher will be contacted with specific instructions. Please submit requests at least two months in advance of your research visit. [unprocessed -- for flag only]
Restrictions on Access
This collection is located off-site. Please consult the Rare Book and Manuscript Library for further information.
Summary
Materials include correspondence and e-mail communications, mission reports, testimonies and interviews, addresses and contact lists, confidential interoffice memos, legal and advocacy material, internal planning and policy material, declassified government and United Nations documents, published and unpublished human rights reports from individuals and fellow non-governmental organizations (NGOs), press clippings and news releases, and maps. Another category of documents consists of HRW reports and briefing papers, as well as press releases and open letters to heads of state, governments and various government agencies.
Summary
Materials related to missions contain unpublished information on sources, cases, and the state of affairs in various countries. They include professional and personal mission notes taken by country researchers and monitors during investigative field trips, testimonies by and interviews with victims of various human rights abuses, pre-mission and post-mission memos, material on research methodology, correspondence and e-mail communications, addresses and contact lists, as well as photographic records.
Summary
Regionally and thematically, these documents cover the various democratic transitions on the African continent such as in South Africa. The papers also comprise such human rights advocacy initiatives as the attempt to prosecute the Rwandan genocide, the international effort to ban land mines, the challenge to ban the use of child soldiers; and the campaigns to promote freedom of expression and academic freedom.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source of acquisition--Human Rights Watch. Method of acquisition--Deposit; Date of acquisition--2006.
Biographical / Historical
In the early 1990s, HRW/Africa expanded its mission beyond its initial concentration on southern Africa and the Horn of Africa to include the entire continent.
Biographical / Historical
The files comprise the following states: Angola, Benin, Burundi, Cameroon, Central African Republic, Chad, Congo, Djibouti, Eritrea, Ethiopia, Guinea, Ivory Coast, Kenya, Liberia, Malawi, Mali, Mauritania, Mozambique, Namibia, Nigeria, Rwanda, Senegal, Sierra Leone, Somalia, South Africa, Sudan, Togo, Uganda, West Africa, Zaire, Zambia, and Zimbabwe.
Biographical / Historical
The files contain archival materials collected or produced by Africa Watch staff, and are arranged alphabetically by country and subject. The files consist of articles, correspondence, memoranda, mission notes, newsletters, press clippings, publications, and general reports.
Ownership and Custodial History
This material was originally deposited at the University of Colorado at Boulder by Human Rights Watch in the 1990s. The material was deposited with the Rare Book and Manuscript Library in 2006.
Accrual
Records76.25 linear ft. 1st accession accumulation, 1988-97
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. Contact rbml@columbia.edu for more information.
Angola -- History -- Civil War, 1975-2002 -- Atrocities; Cameroon -- Social conditions -- 1982-; Ethiopia -- Ethnic relations -- History -- 20th century; Ethiopia -- Politics and government -- 1991-; Ivory Coast -- Politics and government; Mozambique -- History -- 1994-; Mozambique -- Politics and government -- 1994-; Mozambique -- History -- Independence and Civil War, 1975-1994; Nigeria -- Ethnic relations -- Political aspects -- History -- 20th century; Nigeria -- Politics and government -- 1993-2007; Rwanda -- Ethnic relations -- History -- 20th century; Rwanda -- History -- Civil War, 1994 -- Atrocities; Somalia -- Politics and government -- 1991-; South Africa -- Politics and government -- 1994-; South Africa -- Race relations -- Political aspects -- History -- 20th century; Uganda -- History -- 1979-; Uganda -- Social conditions -- 1979-; Zambia -- Politics and government -- 1991-; Zimbabwe -- Foreign relations -- 1980-; Zimbabwe -- Politics and government -- 1990-; Zimbabwe -- Social conditions -- 1980-; Human Rights Watch (Organization)
- Series 1: Karen Sorensen, 1979-1996
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains files relating to Karen Sorensen's work as a HRW/Africa Watch Research Associate during the early to mid-1990s. In 1996, Ms. Sorenson became an HRW on-line research associate. The series is divided into two subseries: subject and country files.
  - Subseries I.1: Subject Files, 1981-1996
    Subject files are arranged alphabetically. The country files are arranged alphabetically and represent the following nations: Algeria, Angola, Benin, Botswana, Burkina Faso, Burundi, Cameroon, Cape Verde, Central African Republic, Chad, Comoros, Congo, Djibouti, Equatorial Guinea, Eritrea, Gabon, Cambia, Ghana, Guinea, Guinea-Bissau, Ivory Coast, Lesotho, Liberia, Madagascar, Malawi, Mali, Mauritania, Mauritius, Morocco, Mozambique, Namibia, Niger, Nigeria, Rwanda, Senegal, Sierra Leone, Somalia, South Africa, Sudan, Swaziland, Tanzania, Togo, Tunisia, Uganda, Zaire, Zambia, Zanzibar and Zimbabwe. The files contain correspondence, Rwandan mission notes and predominantly research files utilized in the compilation of Africa Watch reports produced from 1989 to 1996.
    - Africa Watch (AFW)
      - Articles--AFW
        - Mentions, 1990-1992 (Box 230, Folder 1 to 3)
          Conditions Governing Access
          [Vetted, open]
        - Reports, 1992 (Box 230, Folder 4)
        - Staff, 1991-1992 (Box 230, Folder 5)
      - Press Clippings, 1988 (Box 230, Folder 6)
      - Reports--AFW, 1990-1994; undated (Box 230, Folder 7 to 11)
      - Resumes, 1988 (Box 230, Folder 12)
        [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2064]
    - Academic Freedom
      - General, 1990-1992; (3 Folders) (Box 230, Folder 13 to 15)
        [Unvetted]
      - Kenya, 1990-1991 (Box 230, Folder 16)
    - Accountability for Past Human Rights Abuses, 1989 (Box 230, Folder 17)
    - Administration, 1988-1990 (Box 230, Folder 18)
      [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2070]
    - Africa
      - Academy of Sciences, 1991 (Box 230, Folder 19)
      - Conference, 1988 August (Box 230, Folder 20)
      - Contacts, 1991-1992 (Box 230, Folder 21)
      - Miscellaneous, 1988-1990 (Box 230, Folder 22)
      - United Nations, 1988-1990 (Box 230, Folder 23)
    - African/African-American Relations, 1991 (Box 230, Folder 24)
    - African Centre for Democracy and Human Rights Studies (ACDHRS), 1991 (Box 230, Folder 25)
    - African Charter, 1991-1993 (Box 230, Folder 26)
    - African Commission on Human and Peoples' Rights, 1991-1992 (Box 230, Folder 27)
    - African Studies Association, 1991 (Box 230, Folder 28)
    - Aid
      - Famine Info., 1990-1991 (Box 230, Folder 29)
      - General, 1990-1992 (Box 230, Folder 30)
    - Amnesty International, 1988-1992 (Box 230, Folder 31)
    - Arab Organization for Human Rights, 1988 (Box 230, Folder 32)
    - Asylum, 1992 (Box 230, Folder 33)
    - Black Organizations--United States, 1988 (Box 230, Folder 34)
    - Board
      - List, 1992 (Box 230, Folder 35)
      - Meetings, 1990-1993 (Box 230, Folder 36 to 38)
    - Budget, 1991 (Box 230, Folder 39)
      [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2067]
    - Bush Report, 1991 (Box 231, Folder 1)
    - Carter Center, 1988, 1991 (Box 231, Folder 2)
    - Carver, Richard, 1988 (Box 231, Folder 3)
    - Central Africa, 1991 (Box 231, Folder 4)
    - Commonwealth
      - General, 1991-1992 (Box 231, Folder 5)
      - African NGO Meeting, 1991 October 11 (Box 231, Folder 6)
      - Commonwealth Conference, 1991 (Box 231, Folder 7)
    - Computer Disks, 1993 (Box 231, Folder 8)
    - Congressional Testimony Burkhalter, Holly--1989 February 2 (Box 231, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence
      - Africa Watch Board--General, 1989-1990 (Box 231, Folder 10)
      - General, 1988, 1990 (Box 231, Folder 11)
      - Rone, Jemera, 1988 (Box 231, Folder 12)
      - Sorensen, Karen, 1988-1990, 1993 (Box 231, Folder 13)
      - Thank You Letters, 1993 (Box 231, Folder 14)
    - Debt, 1991 (Box 231, Folder 15)
    - Democratization, 1991-1992 (Box 231, Folder 16)
    - Directors Meetings--Minutes, 1994 (Box 231, Folder 17)
    - Drought, 1992 (Box 231, Folder 18)
    - East Africa, 1992 (Box 231, Folder 19)
    - Environmental Issues, 1992 (Box 231, Folder 20)
    - Ethnic Conflict, 1991 (Box 231, Folder 21)
    - European Community, 1991, 1993 (Box 231, Folder 22)
    - Famine, 1990-1993 (Box 231, Folder 23 to 24)
      [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2068]
    - Finances, 1991-1992 (Box 231, Folder 25)
    - Forensics, 1989-1990, 1992 (Box 231, Folder 26)
    - France, 1992 (Box 231, Folder 27)
    - Franco-African Summit, 1992 October (Box 231, Folder 28)
    - Fund for Free Expression (FFE), 1991-1992 (Box 231, Folder 29)
    - Funding Proposals, 1991-1992 (Box 231, Folder 30)
    - Fundraising, 1991 (Box 231, Folder 31)
    - General, 1990-1992; (5 Folders) (Box 231, Folder 32 to 36)
    - Health, 1989-1990 (Box 231, Folder 37)
    - Horn of Africa, 1988-1992; (3 Folders) (Box 232, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Human Rights--General, 1990,1992 (Box 232, Folder 4)
    - Human Rights Watch
      - London Office, 1991 (Box 232, Folder 5)
      - Memos, 1991-1994; (4 Folders) (Box 232, Folder 6 to 9)
      - Papers, 1990 (Box 232, Folder 10)
    - Illegal State Killings, 1989 (Box 232, Folder 11)
    - Immigrants in Europe, 1991-1992 (Box 232, Folder 12)
    - Integration, undated (Box 232, Folder 13)
    - Institute for a Democratic Alternative for South Africa (IDASA), 1991 (Box 232, Folder 14)
    - International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC), 1981-1988, 1991-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 232, Folder 15 to 16)
    - International Human Rights Internship Program
      - General, 1990-1992 (Box 232, Folder 17)
      - Hussein, Siddiq, 1990 (Box 232, Folder 18)
      - Lumumba, Stanislaus, 1990 (Box 232, Folder 19)
      - Nwankwo, Clement, 1990 (Box 232, Folder 20)
    - International Law, 1989-1991 (Box 232, Folder 21)
    - International Monetary Fund, 1991-1992 (Box 232, Folder 22)
    - International Organizations--Press Clippings, 1991 (Box 232, Folder 23)
    - International Society for Human Rights (ISHR), 1991 (Box 232, Folder 24)
    - Interns, 1990-1991 (Box 232, Folder 25)
    - Islam and Human Rights, 1992 (Box 232, Folder 26)
    - Justice and Reconciliation Committee, 1988 (Box 232, Folder 27)
    - l'a.c.a.t. (action des chrétiens pour l'abolition de la torture, 1991 (Box 232, Folder 28)
    - Landmines, 1991-1992 (Box 232, Folder 29)
    - Laws of War, 1991-1992 (Box 232, Folder 30)
    - Lawyers for Human Rights, 1989-1990 (Box 232, Folder 31)
    - Media, 1991 (Box 232, Folder 32)
    - Médecins du Monde, 1988 (Box 232, Folder 33)
    - Memorandums, 1990-1992, 1994, (6 Folders) (Box 232, Folder 34 to 39)
    - Minority Rights Group, undated (Box 233, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1988-1992 (Box 233, Folder 2)
    - Monitors
      - Africa, 1988 (Box 233, Folder 3)
      - Event, 1991 (Box 233, Folder 4)
    - Musicians & Human Rights, 1991 (Box 233, Folder 5)
    - Network of Activists and Researchers on Integrated Human Rights in Africa (NARIHRA), 1991 (Box 233, Folder 6)
    - Newspapers, 1991 (Box 233, Folder 7)
    - Obstacles to Justice--Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 233, Folder 8)
    - Omaar, Rakiya--Correspondence, 1988-1990; (2 Folders) (Box 233, Folder 9 to 10)
    - Oxford Committee for Famine Relief (Oxfam), 1992 (Box 233, Folder 11)
    - Parliamentarians for Global Action, 1992 (Box 233, Folder 12)
    - PEN American Center, 1991, 1993 (Box 233, Folder 13)
    - Personnel, 1990 (Box 233, Folder 14)
      [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2066]
    - Policies, 1993-1994 (Box 233, Folder 15)
    - Press Issues--Africa, 1988 (Box 233, Folder 16)
    - PR Firms, 1990-1991 (Box 233, Folder 17)
    - Publications--Various, 1994-1996; (3 Folders) (Box 233, Folder 18 to 20)
    - Refugees
      - General, 1988, 1990-1991, 1993 (Box 233, Folder 21)
      - Issues, 1988-1992 (Box 233, Folder 22)
      - United States, 1991-1992 (Box 233, Folder 23)
      - U.S. Committee for Refugees, 1983-1990 (Box 233, Folder 24)
    - Religion, 1992 (Box 233, Folder 25)
    - Rone, Jemera--Contacts--Africa, 1988 (Box 233, Folder 26)
    - Southern Africa, 1992 (Box 233, Folder 27)
    - Television (TV), 1991 (Box 233, Folder 28)
    - Torture, 1992 (Box 233, Folder 29)
    - Trade Unions, 1992 (Box 233, Folder 30)
    - Training, 1991-1992 (Box 233, Folder 31)
    - United Kingdom--Aid, 1991-1992 (Box 233, Folder 32)
    - United Nations
      - General, 1990-1994; (3 Folders) (Box 234, Folder 1 to 3)
      - UN High Commissioner for Refugees, 1988 (Box 234, Folder 4)
    - United States
      - General, 1991-1992 (Box 234, Folder 5)
      - Policy--Africa, 1991-1992 (Box 234, Folder 6)
      - U.S. Department of State--Statements, 1988 (Box 234, Folder 7)
      - U.S. Information Agency (USIA), 1991 (Box 234, Folder 8)
    - Vigilantes and Violence, 1992 (Box 234, Folder 9)
    - Welch, Claude E. Making Rights Human: NGOs and the Protection of Human Rights in Africa, 1993-1994 (Box 234, Folder 10)
    - Wstern Sahara, 1992 (Box 234, Folder 11)
    - Witchcraft, 1992 (Box 234, Folder 12)
    - Women's Issues, 1992-1993 (Box 234, Folder 13)
    - Women's Rights
      - General, 1991-1992 (Box 234, Folder 14)
      - Project, 1991 (Box 234, Folder 15)
    - World Bank, 1988, 1992 (Box 234, Folder 16)
    - World Food Program, 1991-1992 (Box 234, Folder 17)
    - World University Service, 1991 (Box 234, Folder 18)
    - Writers' Project
      - Correspondence, 1991-1992; (2 Folders) (Box 234, Folder 19 to 20)
      - Publications/Reports, 1989-1992 (Box 234, Folder 21)
    - The African Files, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 1)
    - AIDS, 1990-1991, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 2)
    - Association of Concerned African Scholars, 1992-1993 (Box 235, Folder 3)
    - BBC Focus on Africa, 1993 (Box 235, Folder 4)
    - Clinton Administration, 1993 (Box 235, Folder 5)
    - Committee to Protect Journalists, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 6)
    - CSIS Africa Notes, 1993-1994 (Box 235, Folder 7)
    - Economic Policies/Business Relations, 1993-1994 (Box 235, Folder 8)
    - Educational Policies, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 9)
    - Foreign Aid, 1992-1994 (Box 235, Folder 10)
    - Foreign Policy Issues, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 11)
    - International Freedom of Expression Exchange Clearing House, 1993 (Box 235, Folder 12)
    - NATO, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 13)
    - Op Ed/Commentary, 1993-1994 (Box 235, Folder 14)
    - Organisation of African Unity (OAU), 1991-1992 (Box 235, Folder 15)
    - Organizacion Mundial Contra La Tortura, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 16)
    - Political Conflicts/Political Issues, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 17)
    - Population Control, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 18)
    - Reporters Sans Frontieres, 1993 (Box 235, Folder 19)
    - SWB, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 20)
  - Subseries I.2: Country Files, 1979-1995
    The country files are arranged alphabetically and represent the following nations: Algeria, Angola, Benin, Botswana, Burkina Faso, Burundi, Cameroon, Cape Verde, Central African Republic, Chad, Comoros, Congo, Djibouti, Equatorial Guinea, Eritrea, Gabon, Cambia, Ghana, Guinea, Guinea-Bissau, Ivory Coast, Lesotho, Liberia, Madagascar, Malawi, Mali, Mauritania, Mauritius, Morocco, Mozambique, Namibia, Niger, Nigeria, Rwanda, Senegal, Sierra Leone, Somalia, South Africa, Sudan, Swaziland, Tanzania, Togo, Tunisia, Uganda, Zaire, Zambia, Zanzibar and Zimbabwe. The files contain correspondence, Rwandan mission notes and predominantly research files utilized in the compilation of Africa Watch reports produced from 1989 to 1996.
    - Algeria--General, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 21)
    - Angola
      - Africa Today, 1987 (Box 235, Folder 22)
      - Africa Watch Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 235, Folder 23)
      - Amnesty International, 1988-1990 (Box 235, Folder 24)
      - Articles and Wires, 1991-1992 (Box 235, Folder 25)
      - Catholic Institute for International Relations (CIIR), 1993 (Box 235, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence (Box 235)
      - General, 1991-1993 (Box 235, Folder 27)
      - General, 1988-1990, 1992 (Box 235, Folder 28)
      - Foreign Broadcast Information Service (FBIS)--Daily Reports, 1988-1991 (Box 235, Folder 29)
      - Human Rights Groups--Outside, 1992 (Box 235, Folder 30)
      - International Committee of the Red Cross, 1982-1988 (Box 235, Folder 31)
      - Laws--Background, 1992 (Box 235, Folder 32)
      - Material--Western Governments, 1991 (Box 235, Folder 33)
      - Op Ed/Commentary, 1993 (Box 235, Folder 34)
      - Political Conflict/Government Policy, 1993-1994 (Box 235, Folder 35)
      - Press Clippings, 1989-1993; (6 Folders) (Box 235, Folder 36 to 41)
      - Publications/Reports, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 42)
      - Radio/TV Excerpts, 1989 (Box 235, Folder 43)
      - South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO), 1989 (Box 235, Folder 44)
      - United States-Angola Relations, 1993 (Box 235, Folder 45)
      - U.S. Committee for Refugees, 1987 (Box 235, Folder 46)
    - Benin--Press Clippings, 1989-1993; (4 Folders) (Box 235, Folder 47 to 50)
    - Botswana
      - Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 235, Folder 51)
    - Burkina Faso
      - Articles and Wires, 1991 (Box 236, Folder 1)
      - Material Western Governments, 1991-1992 (Box 236, Folder 2)
      - Press Clippings, 1989-1991 (Box 236, Folder 3)
      - Reports, 1990-1992 (Box 236, Folder 4)
    - Burundi
      - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 236, Folder 5)
      - Op Ed/Commentary, 1994 (Box 236, Folder 6)
      - Political Conflict, 1994 (Box 236, Folder 7)
      - Politics/Government, 1993 (Box 236, Folder 8)
      - Reports/Publications, 1994 (Box 236, Folder 9)
    - Cameroon
      - Africa Watch, 1990-1992 (Box 236, Folder 10)
      - Amnesty International, 1989-1993 (Box 236, Folder 11)
      - Anyangwe, Carlson The Magistracy and the Bar in Cameroon, 1989 (Box 236, Folder 12)
      - Background, 1990 (Box 236, Folder 13)
      - Cameroon Monitor, 1986-1990 (Box 236, Folder 14)
      - Contacts, undated (Box 236, Folder 15)
        [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2071]
      - Conversations, 1990-1991 (Box 236, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 236, Folder 17)
      - Democratization, 1990 (Box 236, Folder 18)
      - Demonstrations, 1990 (Box 236, Folder 19)
      - Freedom of Expression, 1990 (Box 236, Folder 20)
      - Freedom of Press, 1990-1991 (Box 236, Folder 21)
      - General, 1989-1991 (Box 236, Folder 22)
      - Government, 1988-1990 (Box 236, Folder 23)
      - Judiciary/Bar, 1990 (Box 236, Folder 24)
      - Laws/Legislation, 1979, 1990-1991 (Box 236, Folder 25)
      - Mukong, Albert, 1989-1991 (Box 236, Folder 26)
      - National Democratic Institute for International Affairs, 1991 (Box 236, Folder 27)
      - Njawe, Pius--Trial, 1990-1991 (Box 236, Folder 28)
      - Obstacles to Justice
        - Articles and Clippings, 1990-1991 (Box 236, Folder 29)
        - Letters and Materials Received, 1991 (Box 236, Folder 30)
        - Letters Sent Out, 1991-1992 (Box 236, Folder 31)
        - Questionnaires, 1991 (Box 236, Folder 32)
        - Resource Materials, undated; (2 Folders) (Box 236, Folder 33 to 34)
        - Transcribed Interviews, 1991 (Box 236, Folder 35)
        - Political Parties, 1990 (Box 236, Folder 36)
        - Political Prisoners, 1989-1990 (Box 236, Folder 37)
        - Press Clippings, 1988-1992; (6 Folders) (Box 237, Folder 1 to 6)
        - Publications, 1987 (Box 237, Folder 7)
        - Students, 1990 (Box 237, Folder 8)
        - United States, 1990-1991 (Box 237, Folder 9)
        - Yondo Black Trial, 1990 (Box 237, Folder 10)
      - Cape Verde--Press Clippings, 1990-1991 (Box 237, Folder 11)
      - Central African Republic, 1990-1993 (Box 237, Folder 12)
      - Chad
        - Amnesty International, 1993 (Box 237, Folder 13)
        - General Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 237, Folder 14)
        - Human Rights Groups--Outside, 1991-1992 (Box 237, Folder 15)
        - Press Clippings, 1987-1992; (3 Folders) (Box 237, Folder 16 to 18)
        - Reports, 1992 (Box 237, Folder 19)
      - Comoros--Press Clippings, 1989-1992 (Box 238, Folder 1)
      - Congo
        - Brazzaville, 1991 (Box 238, Folder 2)
        - Press Clippings, 1989-1993; (2 Folders) (Box 238, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Djibouti
        - Articles and Wires, 1989, 1992 (Box 238, Folder 5)
        - Human Rights Groups--Outside, 1991 (Box 238, Folder 6)
        - Press Clippings, 1989, 1991-1992 (Box 238, Folder 7)
      - Equatorial Guinea
        - Amnesty International, 1993 (Box 238, Folder 8)
        - Press Clippings, 1989-1993 (Box 238, Folder 9)
      - Eritrea
        - Civil Rights Issues, 1993 (Box 238, Folder 10)
        - Politics/Government Policy, 1992 (Box 238, Folder 11)
        - Press Clippings, 1992 (Box 238, Folder 12)
        - Publications/Reports, undated (Box 238, Folder 13)
      - Gabon
        - Gabonese--African American Relations, 1993 (Box 238, Folder 14)
        - Press Clippings, 1989-1992; (2 Folders) (Box 238, Folder 15 to 16)
      - Gambia—Press Clippings, 1988-1992, 1994 (Box 238, Folder 17)
      - Ghana
        - Africa Watch, 1991-1992 (Box 238, Folder 18)
        - Amnesty International, 1988-1990, 1993 (Box 238, Folder 19)
        - Articles and Wires, 1992 (Box 238, Folder 20)
        - Economy, 1994 (Box 238, Folder 21)
        - Environmental Issues, 1994 (Box 238, Folder 22)
        - General Correspondence, 1991 (Box 238, Folder 23)
        - Human Rights Groups--Outside, 1991-1992 (Box 238, Folder 24)